Sinia Reaves Brewer Harris papers, Inclusive: 1932-1979, Bulk: 1939-1943
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Sinia Reaves Brewer Harris papers
Inclusive: 1932-1979, Bulk: 1939-1943
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3016
Harris, Sinia Reaves, 1909-2004.
1 document box and 1 folder in an oversized box
The Sinia Reaves Brewer Harris papers contain correspondence, clippings, photographs, manuals, and other materials documenting Harris' life and work as a a schoolteacher and project director for the National Youth Administration.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Sinia Reaves Brewer Harris (1909-2004), the second daughter and third child of John Henry and Leona Ethel Dodson Reaves, was born 1909 November 25 in Milam County, Texas. She received her B.S. degree in Physical Education at Southwest Texas State University in San Marcos in 1938. She previously attended the University of Texas in Austin in 1937. Harris married Samuel Stephen Brewer on 1928 July 15. The couple had one daughter together, Marion Dolores Brewer, born on 1929 April 27. Sinia and Samuel Brewer divorced in 1941 May. She married Charles Louis Harris on 1942 November 26.
Sinia Reaves Brewer Harris was the National Youth Administration’s project director (resident supervisor) for two facilities in Texas, Brenham and Corpus Christi, as well as the summer program in San Marcos. The National Youth Administration was a New Deal agency that provided work and education for American youth, between ages of 16 to 25, sponsored by the presidency of Franklin D. Roosevelt. At the time Harris was involved, Lyndon B. Johnson was the head of the Texas division. In Brenham, Harris oversaw the Blinn College Girls’ Training School, which trained young women in the fields of recreation, office skills, and radio communication. In Corpus Christi, she oversaw the Defense Industrial Training Project at the Corpus Christi Defense Training Center, which was set up to train women to perform the tasks of historically male-dominated jobs so the men could serve in World War II.
Additionally, Harris assisted in creating co-educational programs in Waco and Inks Dam, Texas. She was the Civilian Personnel Officer at Reese Air Force Base in Lubbock, Texas and at the James Connally Air Force Base in Waco, Texas. She was also a private speech teacher for two years in Milam County and a classroom teacher in Belmena and Curry rural schools in Milam County and in Cameron Public Schools for seven and half years. She retired on 1968 September 30 and passed away on 2004 June 21.
Scope and Content
The Sinia Reaves Brewer Harris Collection consists of three series: Personal, National Youth Administration, and Lyndon B. Johnson Clippings. The Personal series has teaching certificates, project planning materials, and alumni newsletters. The National Youth Administration series is further arranged into four folders: General, Brenham, Corpus Christi, and San Marcos. This series consists of many photographs, personal correspondences to family, official correspondences to former NYA officials, training manuals, certificates, and articles. The Lyndon B. Johnson Clippings series contains newspaper and journal articles about the former president, spanning throughout his presidency to his death, as well as one photograph.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, the Sinia Reaves Brewer Harris papers were grouped in six single folders in one box. Items were not in chronological order, but were categorized by specific city in the National Youth Administration (General, Brenham, Corpus Christi, and San Marcos), along with Personal and Lyndon B. Johnson Clippings groups.
Currently, the Sinia Reaves Brewer Harris papers include three series: I. Personal, II. National Youth Administration, III. Lyndon B. Johnson Clippings. Original overall series and folder subject terms were kept; specific cities now all under second series of National Youth Administration (General, Brenham, San Marcos, and Corpus Christi). Items are now mostly in chronological order depending on series and folders in series.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3016. Acquired 1991-05-08
Related Resources
Related references
“Central Texas Obituaries.” Temple Daily Telegram, 2004 June 23. Accessed 2021 January 20.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.
Subjects (Organizations)
United States National Youth Administration
Places
Texas -- Photographs.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Handbooks and manuals.; Photographs.
- Personal, 1933-1970; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains correspondences, newsletters, teaching contracts, project notes, and photographs. This series is in good condition.
  - General, 1933-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Southwest Texas State College, 1938-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Teacher Certificates, 1932-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Winter Formal, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- National Youth Administration, 1936-1979; 2
  This series contains correspondences, certificates, training materials, manuals, newspaper clippings, and photographs. This series is in good condition.
  - General, Lyndon Baines Johnson Library 1979 Reunion (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General, Manuals, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photograph, undated (Box OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Brenham, Photographs, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brenham, Correspondences, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brenham, Manuals, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - San Marcos, General, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - San Marcos, Newspaper, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Corpus Christi, Photographs, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Corpus Christi, Correspondences, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lyndon B. Johnson Clippings, 1964-1973; 3
  This series contains newspaper clippings, journal articles, and one photograph. This series is in good condition.
  - General, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)